<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/">
<channel>

                    <title>Aura</title>
            <link></link>
            <language>en-us</language> 
            <description>Science X internet news portal provides the latest news on science including: Physics, Nanotechnology, Life Sciences, Space Science, Earth Science, Environment, Health and Medicine.</description>

                            <item>
                    <title>&#039;Toothpick grooves&#039; in ancient fossil human teeth may not be from toothpicks after all</title>
                    <description>For decades, small grooves on ancient human teeth were thought to be evidence of deliberate tool use—people cleaning their teeth with sticks or fibers, or easing gum pain with makeshift &quot;toothpicks.&quot; Some researchers even called it the oldest human habit.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-toothpick-grooves-ancient-fossil-human.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 09:54:48 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678963277</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/toothpick-grooves-in-a-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Magnetic &#039;switchback&#039; detected near Earth for the first time</title>
                    <description>In recent years, NASA&#039;s Parker Solar Probe has given us a close-up look at the sun. Among the probe&#039;s revelations was the presence of numerous kinks, or &quot;switchbacks,&quot; in magnetic field lines in the sun&#039;s outer atmosphere. These switchbacks are thought to form when solar magnetic field lines that point in opposite directions break and then snap together, or &quot;reconnect,&quot; in a new arrangement, leaving telltale zigzag kinks in the reconfigured lines.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-magnetic-switchback-earth.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 12:06:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679143962</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/magnetic-switchback-de.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Satellites record 20-meter high wave, showing the power of ocean swell</title>
                    <description>During recent storms, satellites recorded ocean waves averaging nearly 20 meters high—as tall as the Arc de Triomphe in Paris and the largest ever measured from space. Moreover, satellite data now reveal that ocean swells act as storm &quot;messengers&quot;: even though a storm may never make landfall, its swell can travel vast distances and bring destructive energy to distant coastlines.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-satellites-meter-high-power-ocean.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 11:51:05 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679143062</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/satellites-reveal-the.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Easter Island&#039;s statues actually &#039;walked,&#039; and physics backs it up</title>
                    <description>For years, researchers have puzzled over how the ancient people of Rapa Nui did the seemingly impossible and moved their iconic moai statues. Using a combination of physics, 3D modeling and on-the-ground experiments, a team including faculty at Binghamton University, State University of New York, has confirmed that the statues actually walked—with a little rope and remarkably few people.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-easter-island-statues-physics.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:56:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679056961</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/easter-islands-statues.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Novel drug combination offers hope for men with advanced prostate cancer</title>
                    <description>A new drug combination could significantly delay the progression of a life-threatening form of prostate cancer in men with specific genetic mutations, finds a major international trial led by UCL researchers.</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-drug-combination-men-advanced-prostate.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 05:00:02 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678963284</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2021/prostate-cancer.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>New species of deep-sea shark and crab discovered off Western Australia</title>
                    <description>Researchers have described a new species of deep-sea lanternshark and crab, both with the help of specimens collected from a CSIRO-led 2022 voyage of CSIRO research vessel (RV) Investigator.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-species-deep-sea-shark-crab.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:28:18 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678968896</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/new-species-of-deep-se-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>She saw a car-sized object above a Texas farm and found a wayward hunk of NASA equipment</title>
                    <description>When Ann Walter looked outside her rural West Texas home, she didn&#039;t know what to make of the bulky object slowly drifting across the sky.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-car-sized-texas-farm-wayward.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 04:28:23 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679289286</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/she-saw-a-car-sized-ob.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Researchers unearth origins of Ancient Egypt&#039;s Karnak Temple</title>
                    <description>Researchers have carried out the most comprehensive geoarchaeological survey of Egypt&#039;s Karnak Temple near Luxor—one of the ancient world&#039;s largest temple complexes and a UNESCO World Heritage site welcoming millions of tourists every year.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-unearth-ancient-egypt-karnak-temple.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 08:47:59 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678959270</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/research-unearths-orig.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Physicists detect water&#039;s ultraviolet fingerprint in interstellar comet 3I/ATLAS</title>
                    <description>For millions of years, a fragment of ice and dust drifted between the stars—like a sealed bottle cast into the cosmic ocean. This summer, that bottle finally washed ashore in our solar system and was designated 3I/ATLAS, only the third known interstellar comet. When Auburn University scientists pointed NASA&#039;s Neil Gehrels Swift Observatory toward it, they made a remarkable find: the first detection of hydroxyl (OH) gas from this object, a chemical fingerprint of water.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-physicists-ultraviolet-fingerprint-interstellar-comet.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 12:28:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679058881</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/physicists-uncork-a-me.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Scientists reverse Alzheimer&#039;s in mice using nanoparticles</title>
                    <description>A research team co-led by the Institute for Bioengineering of Catalonia (IBEC) and West China Hospital Sichuan University (WCHSU), working with partners in the UK, has demonstrated a nanotechnology strategy that reverses Alzheimer&#039;s disease in mice.</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-scientists-reverse-alzheimer-mice-nanoparticles.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 20:00:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678960542</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/scientists-reverse-alz.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>First device based on &#039;optical thermodynamics&#039; can route light without switches</title>
                    <description>A team of researchers at the Ming Hsieh Department of Electrical and Computer Engineering has created a new breakthrough in photonics: the design of the first optical device that follows the emerging framework of optical thermodynamics.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-device-based-optical-thermodynamics-route.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:29:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679051742</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/usc-team-demonstrates.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Body illusion helps unlock memories, new study finds</title>
                    <description>New research has discovered that briefly altering how we perceive our own body can help unlock autobiographical memories—potentially even those from the early stages of childhood.</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-body-illusion-memories.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 05:00:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679131301</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/body-illusion-helps-un.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>When mathematics meets aesthetics: Tessellations as a precise tool for solving complex problems</title>
                    <description>In a recent study, mathematicians from Freie Universität Berlin have demonstrated that planar tiling, or tessellation, is much more than a way to create a pretty pattern. Consisting of a surface covered by one or more geometric shapes with no gaps and no overlaps, tessellations can also be used as a precise tool for solving complex mathematical problems.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-mathematics-aesthetics-tessellations-precise-tool.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 12:10:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679316546</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/when-mathematics-meets.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Novel blood test for chronic fatigue achieves 96% accuracy</title>
                    <description>Scientists at the University of East Anglia and Oxford Biodynamics have developed a high accuracy blood test to diagnose chronic fatigue syndrome, also known as myalgic encephalomyelitis (ME/CFS).</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-blood-chronic-fatigue-accuracy.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 20:00:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679068901</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/chronic-fatigue.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Egypt reopens Amenhotep III&#039;s tomb after over 20 years of renovation</title>
                    <description>Egypt on Saturday opened a tomb of a pharaoh for visitors after more than two decades of renovation in the southern city of Luxor, as it prepares for the official opening of the Grand Egyptian Museum in Cairo.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-egypt-reopens-amenhotep-iii-tomb.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 12:29:35 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678885777</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/egypt-reopens-amenhote-2.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>By removing common biases, study debunks U-shaped happiness curve with age</title>
                    <description>Many survey-based studies have been conducted to try to understand how happiness changes over a person&#039;s lifetime. While there have been a few different outcomes, the most common has been the U-shaped curve. This pattern indicates that, on average, people are happier at the beginning of adulthood, they experience a dip during midlife (the so-called &quot;midlife crisis&quot;), and happiness then increases again in old age. Yet, other similar studies have reported inconsistent patterns—steady happiness throughout life, steady increases, steady decreases or even inverse U-shapes.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-common-biases-debunks-happiness-age.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 12:02:10 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679316524</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/idea-that-happiness-fi.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Astronomers discover the most &#039;pristine&#039; star in the known universe</title>
                    <description>Not all stars are created equally. Astronomers believe that the first stars to form after the Big Bang were mostly made of only hydrogen and helium with trace amounts of lithium, as the heavier elements formed later on by nuclear fusion inside the stars. When these stars went supernova, heavier elements spread throughout space and formed more stars. Each successive generation contained more heavy elements, and these elements also became successively heavier.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-astronomers-pristine-star-universe.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 10:30:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679138048</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/astronomers-discover-t-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Event Horizon Telescope images reveal new dark matter detection method</title>
                    <description>According to a new Physical Review Letters study, black holes could help solve the dark matter mystery. The shadowy regions in black hole images captured by the Event Horizon Telescope can act as ultra-sensitive detectors for the invisible material that makes up most of the universe&#039;s matter.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-event-horizon-telescope-images-reveal.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 10:20:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679309891</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/event-horizon-telescop.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Astronomers detect lowest mass dark object ever measured using gravitational lensing</title>
                    <description>Dark matter is an enigmatic form of matter not expected to emit light, yet it is essential to understanding how the rich tapestry of stars and galaxies we see in the night sky evolved. As a fundamental building block of the universe, a key question for astronomers is whether dark matter is smooth or clumpy, as this could reveal what it is made of. Since dark matter cannot be observed directly, its properties can only be determined by observing the gravitational lensing effect, whereby the light from a more distant object is distorted and deflected by the gravity of the dark object.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-astronomers-lowest-mass-dark-gravitational.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 13:19:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679234742</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/mysterious-dark-object.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Nobel Prize in physics goes to 3 scientists whose work advanced quantum technology</title>
                    <description>Three scientists won the Nobel Prize in physics Tuesday for research on the strange behavior of subatomic particles called quantum tunneling that enabled the ultra-sensitive measurements achieved by MRI machines and laid the groundwork for better cellphones and faster computers.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-nobel-prize-physics-scientists-discoveries.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 06:01:36 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679035669</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/nobel-prize-for-physic.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Why Annabelle, Chucky and dolls in general creep us out</title>
                    <description>Toy dolls are having a Halloween moment. And it&#039;s anything but pretty or cute.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-annabelle-chucky-dolls-general.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 09:19:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679133941</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/why-annabelle-chucky-a.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Quantum uncertainty captured in real time using femtosecond light pulses</title>
                    <description>Researchers from the University of Arizona, working with an international team, have captured and controlled quantum uncertainty in real time using ultrafast pulses of light. Their discovery, published in the journal Light: Science &amp; Applications, could lead to more secure communication and the development of ultrafast quantum optics.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-quantum-uncertainty-captured-real-femtosecond.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:40:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678975908</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/quantum-uncertainty-ta.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Image of two black holes circling each other captured for the first time</title>
                    <description>For the first time, astronomers have managed to capture a radio image showing two black holes orbiting each other. The observation confirmed the existence of black hole pairs. In the past, astronomers have only managed to image individual black holes.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-image-black-holes-circling-captured.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 10:20:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679223804</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/scientists-capture-an.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Rare intersex spider among new species discovered in Thailand</title>
                    <description>A new species of spider was recently discovered near a forested area in Nong Rong, Phanom Thuan, Kanchanaburi, in western Thailand. The spiders were presented to researchers at the Chulalongkorn University Museum of Natural History, where they were studied further.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-rare-intersex-spider-species-thailand.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:30:06 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679054902</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/rare-intersex-spider-a.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>The remarkable rise of eBird—the world&#039;s biggest citizen science project</title>
                    <description>The lights in the auditorium darken. The cacophony of voices subsides. The enormous screen comes to life, displaying a satellite image of Australia and the scattering of islands directly to the north. The contrast between the dry, orangey red of most of Australia and the deep green of Papua New Guinea is stark.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-remarkable-ebird-world-biggest-citizen.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 09:20:05 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679134001</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/photographing-birds.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Powerful and precise multi-color lasers now fit on a single chip</title>
                    <description>A few years ago, researchers in Michal Lipson&#039;s lab noticed something remarkable. They were working on a project to improve LiDAR, a technology that uses lightwaves to measure distance. The lab was designing high-power chips that could produce brighter beams of light.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-powerful-precise-multi-lasers-chip.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:22:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679047721</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/powerful-and-precise-m.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>The world&#039;s snow leopards are very similar genetically—findings suggest that doesn&#039;t bode well for their future</title>
                    <description>There are relatively few snow leopards in the world, and it has likely been that way for a long time, a new study indicates. This situation increases their risk of extinction in a changing environment.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-world-leopards-similar-genetically-doesnt.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 13:00:07 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679060376</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/the-worlds-snow-leopar.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Simulations unveil the electrodynamic nature of black hole mergers and other spacetime collisions</title>
                    <description>Gravitational waves are energy-carrying waves produced by the acceleration or disturbance of massive objects. These waves, which were first directly observed in 2015, are known to be produced during various cosmological phenomena, including mergers between two black holes that orbit each other (i.e., binary black holes).</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-simulations-unveil-electrodynamic-nature-black.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 06:30:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679138076</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/simulations-unveil-the.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>&#039;Playing to your strengths&#039; improves well-being in adult ADHD, new research shows</title>
                    <description>Adults with ADHD who recognize and regularly use their personal strengths report better well-being, improved quality of life and fewer mental health difficulties, according to a new international study.</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-playing-strengths-adult-adhd.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:30:10 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678975904</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/creative.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>World&#039;s most sensitive table-top experiment sets new limits on very high-frequency gravitational waves</title>
                    <description>The world&#039;s most sensitive table-top interferometric system—a miniature version of miles-long gravitational-wave detectors like LIGO—has completed its first science run.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-world-sensitive-table-limits-high.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 10:59:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679226342</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/worlds-most-sensitive-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>A safer solvent for organic chemistry labs</title>
                    <description>The solvent dichloromethane, or DCM, is commonly used to strip paint and cut grease. It&#039;s also what generations of chemistry students have used to dissolve pain reliever tablets in a lab exercise designed to teach them how to isolate compounds in a mixture.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-safer-solvent-chemistry-labs.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 12:14:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679058041</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/a-safer-solvent-for-or.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Farmed totoaba could curb poaching</title>
                    <description>The trade of totoaba has all the intrigue of a crime thriller. Dollars and drugs change hands as a criminal cartel vies against the government. Communities and endangered species are caught in the crosshairs of a lucrative illicit trade. It may then come as a surprise that the totoaba is a fish.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-farmed-totoaba-curb-poaching.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 14:48:05 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679153681</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/farmed-totoaba-could-c.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Human exceptionalism is at the root of the ecological crisis, claims evolutionary biologist</title>
                    <description>In the grand story of evolution, the crowning human distinction is our big brain. But our large heads have been slow to recognize a less admirable trait of Homo sapiens—self-centeredness.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-human-exceptionalism-root-ecological-crisis.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 10:29:53 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679224587</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/human-exceptionalism-i.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>DNA repair mechanisms help explain why naked mole-rats live a long life</title>
                    <description>Naked mole-rats are one of nature&#039;s most extraordinary creatures. These burrowing rodents can live for up to 37 years, around ten times longer than relatives of a similar size. But what is the secret to their extreme longevity? How are they able to delay the decay and decline that befalls other rodents? The answer, at least in part, is due to a switch in a common protein that boosts DNA repair, according to new research published in the journal Science.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-dna-mechanisms-naked-mole-rats.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Sun, 12 Oct 2025 01:06:58 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679322131</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/naked-mole-rat.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>From barks to words: Researchers aim to translate dog sounds with AI</title>
                    <description>Ever wonder what your dog is trying to say? Well, a University of Texas at Arlington researcher is aiming to turn barks, howls and whimpers of man&#039;s best friend into intelligible speech—a kind of Rosetta Stone of woof.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-barks-words-aim-dog-ai.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:50:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679217870</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/dog-bark.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Alzheimer&#039;s disease research in brain tissue from African American donors points to roles for many novel genes</title>
                    <description>The prevalence of Alzheimer&#039;s disease (AD) is approximately two times higher in African Americans (AA) compared to white/European-ancestry (EA) individuals living in the U.S. Some of this is due to social determinants of health such as disparities in health care access and quality of education, biases in testing and higher rates of AD risk factors such as cardiovascular disease and diabetes in those who identify as African American.</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-alzheimer-disease-brain-tissue-african.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 07:00:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679071206</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/alzheimers-5.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Clam shells sound alarm over unstable North Atlantic currents</title>
                    <description>Bivalves, such as clams, oysters and mussels, record seasonal environmental changes in their shells, making them living chronicles of climate history. A new study of bivalve shells has detected two major episodes of instability in the North Atlantic Ocean&#039;s circulation systems, suggesting that the region may be heading toward a tipping point that could trigger sudden, dramatic changes in global weather patterns.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-clam-shells-alarm-unstable-north.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 09:53:52 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678963228</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/clam-shells-sound-the.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Bay scallops surge on Virginia&#039;s Eastern Shore</title>
                    <description>Virginia&#039;s bay scallop population is experiencing an unprecedented resurgence, thanks to years of dedicated restoration work led by the Batten School &amp; VIMS Eastern Shore Laboratory (ESL) in Wachapreague. Once locally extinct due to habitat loss, bay scallops are now multiplying exponentially in the restored eelgrass meadows of the Eastern Shore&#039;s southern coastal bays, possibly setting the stage for a future recreational fishery.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-bay-scallops-surge-virginia-eastern.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 16:47:02 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679247221</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/bay-scallops-surge-on-5.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Sped-up evolution may help bacteria take hold in gut microbiome</title>
                    <description>Everywhere you go, you carry a population of microbes in your gastrointestinal tract that outnumber the human cells making up your body.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-sped-evolution-bacteria-gut-microbiome.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 15:32:05 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679242721</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/sped-up-evolution-may.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Plant-based lubricant outperforms talc and microplastics, offering a nontoxic alternative for seed dispersal</title>
                    <description>Researchers have developed a new class of nontoxic, biodegradable solid lubricants that can be used to facilitate seed dispersal using modern farming equipment, with the goal of replacing existing lubricants that pose human and environmental toxicity concerns. The paper, &quot;Graph Theory Based Bioderived Solid Lubricant,&quot; is published in the journal Matter.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-based-lubricant-outperforms-talc-microplastics.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 11:00:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678963001</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/engineers-develop-soli.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>How black holes produce powerful relativistic jets</title>
                    <description>A hundred years before the Event Horizon Telescope Collaboration released the first image of a black hole in 2019—located at the heart of the galaxy M87—astronomer Heber Curtis had already discovered a strange jet protruding from the galaxy&#039;s center. Today, we know this to be the jet of the black hole M87*. Such jets are also emitted by other black holes. Theoretical astrophysicists at Goethe University have now developed a numerical code to describe with high mathematical precision how black holes transform their rotational energy into such ultra-fast jets.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-black-holes-powerful-relativistic-jets.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:05:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678963901</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/how-black-holes-produc.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Ancient DNA reveals prehistoric connections and a patrilineal society in early China</title>
                    <description>Scientists from Peking University have uncovered new genetic evidence that sheds light on how prehistoric people in China interacted, migrated, and built their communities. Led by Professors Huang Yanyi and Pang Yuhong from the Biomedical Pioneering Innovation Center (BIOPIC), the research reveals the first direct genetic proof of a patrilineal social system in Neolithic China.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-ancient-dna-reveals-prehistoric-patrilineal.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 09:26:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679220761</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/ancient-dna-reveals-pr.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Eco-friendly technology removes toxic PFAS from water</title>
                    <description>Rice University researchers, in collaboration with international partners, have developed the first eco-friendly technology to rapidly capture and destroy toxic &quot;forever chemicals&quot; (PFAS) in water. The findings, recently published in Advanced Materials, mark a major step toward addressing one of the world&#039;s most persistent environmental threats.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-eco-friendly-technology-toxic-pfas.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:19:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679065541</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/eco-friendly-technolog-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>3I/ATLAS&#039;s coma proves another cometary formation theory</title>
                    <description>Interstellar visitor 3I/ATLAS has been constantly changing as it makes its way through our solar system. That&#039;s to be expected, as, for the first time in potentially billions of years, it&#039;s getting close to the energy put out by a star.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-3iatlas-coma-cometary-formation-theory.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:55:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678981301</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/3iatlass-coma-proves-a.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Composite metal foam endures over 1 million load cycles at 400°C and 600°C</title>
                    <description>New research shows that composite metal foam (CMF) is incredibly resilient at high temperatures, able to withstand repeated heavy loads even at temperatures of 400°C and 600°C. Coupled with the material&#039;s high strength-to-weight ratio, the finding suggests that CMF could be used in applications ranging from automobile engines to aerospace components to nuclear power technologies.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-composite-metal-foam-million-400c.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:29:39 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679048173</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/some-like-it-hot-compo.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Energy storage and new materials eyed for chemistry Nobel</title>
                    <description>The development of new compounds and novel ways of storing energy are some of the research fields commentators say could be contenders for the Nobel Prize in Chemistry announced Wednesday.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-energy-storage-materials-eyed-chemistry.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 05:39:07 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679120740</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/the-norwegian-nobel-in.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>From engines to nanochips: Physicists redefine how heat really moves</title>
                    <description>Heat has always been something we thought we understood. From baking bread to running engines, the idea seemed simple: heat spreads out smoothly, like water soaking through a sponge. That simple picture, written down by Joseph Fourier 200 years ago, became the foundation of modern science and engineering.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-nanochips-physicists-redefine.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:44:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678973434</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/from-engines-to-nanoch.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Unified model explains extreme jet streams on all giant planets</title>
                    <description>One of the most notable properties of the giant planets in our solar system—Jupiter, Saturn, Uranus and Neptune—are the extreme winds observed around their equators. While some of these planets have eastward equatorial winds, others have a westward jet stream. For the first time, an international team of scientists led by Leiden Observatory and SRON, can explain the winds on all the giant planets using one model.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-extreme-jet-streams-giant-planets.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:00:05 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678970862</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/new-model-explains-ext-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Algorithm reveals &#039;magic sizes&#039; for assembling programmable icosahedral shells at minimal cost</title>
                    <description>Over the past decade, experts in the field of nanotechnology and materials science have been trying to devise architectures composed of small structures that spontaneously arrange themselves following specific patterns. Some of these architectures are based on so-called icosahedral shells, structures with 20 different triangular faces that are symmetrically organized.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-algorithm-reveals-magic-sizes-programmable.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:30:02 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679054911</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/a-new-algorithm-for-th.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Repetitive negative thinking mediates relationship between self-esteem and burnout in students, study finds</title>
                    <description>When people are highly stressed for prolonged periods of time, they can sometimes experience a state known as burnout, characterized by pronounced emotional, mental and physical exhaustion. The stressors leading to burnout could be personal, such as family conflicts or the end of a relationship, as well as academic or professional, such as studying a lot for exams or working long hours while taking very few breaks or vacations.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-repetitive-negative-relationship-esteem-burnout.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 09:00:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678703984</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/student-thinking.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>&#039;Solids full of holes&#039;: Nobel-winning materials explained</title>
                    <description>The chemistry Nobel was awarded on Wednesday to three scientists who discovered a revolutionary way of making materials full of tiny holes that can do everything from sucking water out of the desert air to capturing climate-warming carbon dioxide.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-solids-full-holes-nobel-materials.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:11:51 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679155098</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/a-demonstration-of-the.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>General relativity could make life possible on planets orbiting white dwarfs</title>
                    <description>In the hunt for extraterrestrial life, we usually look for planets orbiting sun-like stars and icy moons. But there is another possible candidate—planets circling white dwarfs, the hot, dense remnants of dead stars.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-general-life-planets-orbiting-white.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:30:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679047972</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/general-relativity-cou.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Archaeologists uncover ritual platforms that helped pave the way for Chinese unification</title>
                    <description>Archaeologists have excavated three c. 3,000–2,400-year-old ritual structures in Shandong Province, China, indicating that the origins of a shared Chinese cultural identity lie in ceremonial gatherings that sowed the seeds for the political unification of China under the First Emperor. The findings are reported in Antiquity.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-archaeologists-uncover-ritual-platforms-pave.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 05:00:12 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678527102</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/archaeologists-uncover-15.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Could dogs ever talk? New review weighs science, ethics and evolution</title>
                    <description>A new scientific review tackles an age-old question: could dogs ever learn to talk? While barking out full sentences might sound like science fiction, researchers are taking a closer look at the biological and technological possibilities behind enhancing canine communication.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-dogs-science-ethics-evolution.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 12:59:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679147141</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/could-dogs-ever-talk-n.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Multimode quantum entanglement achieved via dissipation engineering</title>
                    <description>A research team led by Prof. Lin Yiheng from the University of Science and Technology of China (USTC), collaborating with Prof. Yuan Haidong from the Chinese University of Hong Kong, succeeded in generating multipartite quantum entangled states across two, three, and five modes using controlled dissipation as a resource. Their study is published in Science Advances.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-multimode-quantum-entanglement-dissipation.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 12:25:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679317901</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/multimode-quantum-enta-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Quantum dynamics on your laptop? New technique moves us closer</title>
                    <description>Imagine zooming into matter at the quantum scale, where tiny particles can interact in more than a trillion configurations at once.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-quantum-dynamics-laptop-technique-closer.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 12:09:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679144142</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/quantum-dynamics-on-yo-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Physical exercise can &#039;train&#039; the immune system</title>
                    <description>In addition to strengthening the muscles, lungs, and heart, regular physical exercise also strengthens the immune system. This finding comes from a study of older adults with a history of endurance training, which involves prolonged physical activity such as long-distance running, cycling, swimming, rowing, and walking.</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-physical-immune.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:44:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679157041</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2022/elderly-exercise.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>How to grow a giant pumpkin, with help from science</title>
                    <description>The pumpkin in Tony Scott&#039;s backyard weighs almost as much as a small car.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-giant-pumpkin-science.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 12:30:07 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678886198</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/how-to-grow-a-giant-pu.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Three scientists win Nobel Prize in chemistry for the development of metal-organic frameworks</title>
                    <description>Three scientists won the Nobel Prize in chemistry Wednesday for their development of new molecular structures that can trap vast quantities of gas inside, laying the groundwork to potentially suck greenhouse gases out of the atmosphere or harvest moisture from desert environments.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-scientists-nobel-prize-chemistry-metal.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 05:55:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679121691</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/susumu-kitagawa-richar-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Astronomers discover ultra-luminous infrared galaxy lurking behind quasar</title>
                    <description>An international team of astronomers has used the Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array (ALMA) to observe a well-known quasar known as the Cloverleaf. As part of the observations, they serendipitously discovered a new ultra-luminous infrared galaxy. The finding was reported September 30 in the Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-astronomers-ultra-luminous-infrared-galaxy.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 08:00:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679203153</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/new-ultra-luminous-inf.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Ancient teeth provide new insight into the lives of the world&#039;s first farming villagers</title>
                    <description>Archaeologists have revealed new insights into how the world&#039;s first farming villagers formed communities, moved across the land and responded to outsiders.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-ancient-teeth-insight-world-farming.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:00:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679046401</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/ancient-teeth-provide.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>A new scalable approach to realize a quantum communication network based on ytterbium-171 atoms</title>
                    <description>Quantum networks, systems consisting of connected quantum computers, quantum sensors or other quantum devices, hold the potential of enabling faster and safer communications. The establishment of these networks relies on a quantum phenomenon known as entanglement, which entails a link between particles or systems, with the quantum state of one influencing the other even when they are far apart.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-scalable-approach-quantum-communication-network.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 08:30:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679227089</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/a-new-scalable-approac-2.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Quantum fluctuations found hidden beneath classical optical signals in polaritons</title>
                    <description>When optical materials (molecules or solid-state semiconductors) are embedded in tiny photonic boxes, known as optical microcavities, they form hybrid light-matter states known as polaritons. Most of the optical properties of polaritons under weak illumination can be understood using textbook classical optics. Now researchers from UC San Diego show that this is not the entire story: there are quantum fluctuations lurking underneath the classical signal and they reveal a great deal about the molecules in question.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-quantum-fluctuations-hidden-beneath-classical.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 13:34:44 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679235682</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/quantum-fluctuations-f.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>The real reasons Endurance sank—study finds Shackleton knew of ship&#039;s shortcomings</title>
                    <description>Sir Ernest Shackleton&#039;s ship, Endurance, was crushed by Antarctic sea ice and sank in November 1915. Emblematic of the heroic age of Antarctic exploration, it is widely considered the strongest polar ship of its time, albeit with a fatal flaw—a weakness in the rudder that caused the ship to sink.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-real-sank-shackleton-knew-ship.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 06:00:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678701988</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/the-real-reasons-endur-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Colon cancer considered cured after six years when relapse risk falls below 0.5%</title>
                    <description>IRCCS Ospedale Policlinico San Martino with Mayo Clinic and multiple international cancer research centers have delivered a pooled analysis indicating that colon cancer recurrence risk drops below 0.5% by year six after surgery, offering a practical definition of cure.</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-colon-cancer-years-relapse-falls.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 06:30:02 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678968126</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/colon-cancer.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>High-speed onion mist: Cutting technique and blade sharpness affect droplet spray, study shows</title>
                    <description>A new discovery about how cutting onions ejects pungent aerosols up to two-thirds of a meter into the air has led to practical advice for reducing the spray: Cut onions slowly with a sharpened blade or coat an onion in oil before cutting.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-high-onion-mist-technique-blade.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 15:53:16 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679071192</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/mist-opportunity-revea.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Scientists identify a new dendritic nanotubular network in the brain that may contribute to Alzheimer&#039;s disease</title>
                    <description>Neurons in the brain communicate with each other through synapses—connection points that allow the passage of electrical and chemical signals. In non-neuronal cells, direct cell-to-cell connections have been found to occur with the assistance of nanotube structures. In particular, tunneling nanotubes (TNT) have exhibited material exchange in some cell types. These TNTs have been documented in dissociated neurons in the brain, but their presence and function in mature brain neurons was unclear.</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-scientists-dendritic-nanotubular-network-brain.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 07:50:02 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678711014</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/scientists-identify-a-4.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Lizard genetics provide new perspective on evolution</title>
                    <description>Some colorful lizards and a mathematical formula from the finance sector have been used to build a new framework to model evolution.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-lizard-genetics-perspective-evolution.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 04:00:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679071461</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/lizard-genetics-provid.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Observing quantum weirdness in our world: Nobel physics explained</title>
                    <description>The Nobel Prize in Physics was awarded to three scientists on Tuesday for discovering that a bizarre barrier-defying phenomenon in the quantum realm could be observed on an electrical circuit in our classical world.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-quantum-weirdness-world-nobel-physics.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 12:36:52 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679059406</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/the-new-physics-nobel.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Individual electrons trapped and controlled above 1 K, easing cooling limits for quantum computing</title>
                    <description>Researchers from EeroQ, the quantum computing company pioneering electron-on-helium technology, have published a paper, titled &quot;Sensing and Control of Single Trapped Electrons Above 1 Kelvin,&quot;  in Physical Review X that details a significant milestone: the first demonstration of controlling and detecting individual electrons trapped on superfluid helium at temperatures above 1 Kelvin. This work was achieved using on-chip superconducting microwave circuits, a method compatible with existing quantum hardware.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-individual-electrons-easing-cooling-limits.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 14:15:02 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679238101</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/sensing-and-control-of.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Rare Jurassic &#039;sword dragon&#039; prehistoric reptile discovered in the UK</title>
                    <description>A near-complete skeleton found on the UK&#039;s Jurassic Coast has been identified as a new and rare species of ichthyosaur—a type of prehistoric marine reptile that once ruled the ancient oceans.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-rare-jurassic-sword-dragon-prehistoric.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 08:50:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679305002</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/rare-jurassic-sword-dr-2.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>How the Southern Ocean controlled climate and atmospheric carbon dioxide during the lukewarm interglacials</title>
                    <description>Earth&#039;s climate has fluctuated between cold and warm periods for millions of years. During the so-called &quot;lukewarm interglacials&quot;—warm phases between 800,000 and 430,000 years ago—atmospheric CO2 concentrations were only around 240 to 260 ppm (parts per million, i.e., molecules per 1 million molecules of air). Later interglacials reached values of 280 to 300 ppm.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-southern-ocean-climate-atmospheric-carbon.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:19:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678975542</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/how-the-southern-ocean-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Researchers integrate waveguide physics into metasurfaces for advanced light control</title>
                    <description>Ultrathin structures that can bend, focus, or filter light, metasurfaces are reshaping how scientists think about optics. These engineered materials offer precise control over lights behavior, but many conventional designs are held back by inefficiencies. Typically, they rely on local resonances within individual nanostructures, which often leak energy or perform poorly at wide angles. These shortcomings limit their usefulness in areas like sensing, nonlinear optics, and quantum technologies.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-waveguide-physics-metasurfaces-advanced.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:37:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678983821</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/researchers-integrate.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Rare disease possibly identified in 12th century child&#039;s skeletal remains</title>
                    <description>In the journal Childhood in the Past, Ph.D. candidate Duru Yağmur Başaran published the results of an analysis of an over 900-year-old skeleton of a child. The study revealed that a 2.5 to 3.5-year-old child had suffered from a rare disease seldom seen in archaeology.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-rare-disease-possibly-12th-century.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 07:10:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679223752</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/rare-disease-possibly.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Millions rely on dwindling Colorado River—but are kept &#039;in the dark&#039; about fixes, critics say</title>
                    <description>The Colorado River, which provides water across the Southwest, has lost about 20% of its flow in the last quarter-century, and its depleted reservoirs continue to decline. But negotiations aimed at addressing the water shortage are at an impasse, and leaders of environmental groups say the secrecy surrounding the talks is depriving the public of an opportunity to weigh in.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-millions-dwindling-colorado-river-dark.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 08:00:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678955000</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/colorado-river-basin.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Introduced animals change how island plants spread, global study finds</title>
                    <description>On islands, many plants rely on animals such as birds, bats and reptiles to disperse their seeds and help them grow in new places. When native animals go extinct, this naturally reduces seed dispersal.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-animals-island-global.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 16:12:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679158721</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/introduced-animals-cha.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Ancient Patagonian hunter-gatherers took care of their injured and disabled, study finds</title>
                    <description>In a study published in the International Journal of Paleopathology, Dr. Victoria Romano and her colleagues analyzed the bones of 189 hunter-gatherers who lived during the Late Holocene (~4000 to 250 BP) in Patagonia.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-ancient-patagonian-hunter-disabled.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 07:30:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678963258</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/study-finds-ancient-pa-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Saturday Citations: AI chatbots are insincere; childhood memory recall; a tiny chunk of dark matter</title>
                    <description>This week, researchers discovered so-called &quot;switchbacks&quot; in Earth&#039;s magnetic field similar to observations of switchbacks in the sun&#039;s magnetic field. Scientists provided more evidence that ancient Rapa Nui engineers &quot;walked&quot; Easter Island&#039;s iconic statues along carefully designed roads. And satellite imagery revealed a record 20-meter-high ocean wave. We also reported on a unique method for eliciting childhood memories, the smallest chunk of dark matter ever observed, and the pernicious effects of empty praise from chatbots:</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-saturday-citations-ai-chatbots-insincere.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 08:50:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679317280</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/saturday-citations-ai-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Smart cutting system used by female sawflies could transform surgery and reduce patient harm</title>
                    <description>Scientists at Heriot-Watt University have unlocked the secret behind how female sawflies make specific cuts to plants—a discovery that could revolutionize surgical instruments and dramatically reduce the cutting of healthy tissue during operations.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-smart-female-sawflies-surgery-patient.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:08:05 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678964081</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/smart-cutting-system-u.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>How biological motors achieve maximum efficiency</title>
                    <description>Inside nearly every cell of your body, the tiny F1 motor works non-stop to create adenosine triphosphate (ATP), the universal energy source that powers almost every action you take—from breathing to running. While scientists have understood the structure of this molecular machine for years, a key mystery remained: how does its partner, the F0 motor, spin F1 with maximum efficiency?</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-biological-motors-maximum-efficiency.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:30:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678975120</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/how-biological-motors.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Third dimension of data storage: Physicists demonstrate first hybrid skyrmion tubes for higher-density quantum computing</title>
                    <description>Typically, the charge of electrons is used to store and process information in electronics-based devices. In spintronics, the focus is instead on the magnetic moment or on magnetic vortices, so-called skyrmions—the goal is smaller, faster, and more sustainable computers. To further increase storage density, skyrmions will not only be two-dimensional in the future, but will also conquer the third dimension.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-dimension-storage-physicists-hybrid-skyrmion.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:50:05 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678973522</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/third-dimension-of-dat-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Restless leg syndrome&#039;s connection to Parkinson&#039;s disease</title>
                    <description>Three research hospitals in the Republic of Korea are reporting that restless leg syndrome was associated with an increased risk of Parkinson&#039;s disease, with 1.6% of patients with restless leg syndrome developing Parkinson&#039;s disease vs. 1.0% in matched controls and a shorter average time to diagnosis at a 15-year horizon.</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-restless-leg-syndrome-parkinson-disease.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 10:20:05 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679223704</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/legs-on-bed.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>As flight delays loom, SpaceX puts up defense in rocket vs. airplane debate</title>
                    <description>The competition for airspace is just beginning as the space age kicks into high gear on the Space Coast.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-flight-delays-loom-spacex-defense.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 08:10:02 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678955069</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/starship.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Researchers turn coffee and plastic waste into climate solution</title>
                    <description>Researchers at the University of Sharjah have patented a technology designed to capture carbon dioxide (CO₂) from industrial processes before it is released into the atmosphere.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-coffee-plastic-climate-solution.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:59:18 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678985155</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/researchers-turn-coffe-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>How Europe&#039;s largest bat catches and eats birds mid-air</title>
                    <description>After nearly 25 years of research, the mystery has finally been solved: Europe&#039;s largest bat doesn&#039;t just eat small birds—it hunts and captures them more than a kilometer above the ground. And it eats them without landing.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-europe-largest-birds-mid-air.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 14:00:22 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679154581</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/mystery-solved-how-eur.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>The human cost of healthy eating: Some recommended US diets carry higher risk of forced labor in food supply chains</title>
                    <description>Many Americans choose food based on cost and nutrition, but personal values, such as animal welfare and environmental concerns, also shape what ends up on our plates.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-human-healthy-diets-higher-labor.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 05:00:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678985149</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/migrant-farm-worker.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Scientists unlock new patterns of protein behavior in cell membranes</title>
                    <description>Cellular membrane proteins play many important roles throughout the body, including transporting substances in and out of the cell, transmitting signals, speeding up reactions and helping neighboring cells stick together. When they malfunction, it can cause serious diseases including cancer, making them attractive drug targets. But understanding how membrane proteins behave and function can be challenging because their position within the cell&#039;s lipid membrane—a tightly-packed double layer of fat-like molecules—makes them difficult to study.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-scientists-patterns-protein-behavior-cell.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 16:47:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679074421</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/scripps-research-scien.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Order from disordered proteins: Physics-based algorithm designs biomolecules with custom properties</title>
                    <description>In synthetic and structural biology, advances in artificial intelligence have led to an explosion of designing new proteins with specific functions, from antibodies to blood clotting agents, by using computers to accurately predict the 3D structure of any given amino acid sequence.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-disordered-proteins-physics-based-algorithm.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 05:00:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678704281</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/order-from-disordered.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Physicists develop new quantum sensor at the atomic lattice scale</title>
                    <description>From computer chips to quantum dots—technological platforms were only made possible thanks to a detailed understanding of the used solid-state materials, such as silicon or more complex semiconductor materials. This understanding also includes being able to identify and control irregularities in the crystal lattice of such materials.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-physicists-quantum-sensor-atomic-lattice.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 10:12:19 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679050735</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/research-team-develops-3.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>World&#039;s first known butt-drag fossil trace was left by a rock hyrax in South Africa 126,000 years ago</title>
                    <description>Rock hyraxes, known in southern Africa more often as &quot;dassies,&quot; are furry, thickset creatures with short legs and no discernible tails. They spend much of their time sunning themselves on rocky outcrops.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-world-butt-fossil-left-hyrax.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:50:07 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678973532</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/worlds-first-known-but.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Programmable optical chip merges photons to change color</title>
                    <description>Cornell researchers have built a programmable optical chip that can change the color of light by merging photons, without requiring a new chip for new colors.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-programmable-optical-chip-merges-photons.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 12:00:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679143601</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/programmable-optical-c.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Losing Nemo: Almost all marine aquarium fish in the US are caught in the wild</title>
                    <description>New research has revealed that about 90% of marine aquarium fish sold by online retailers in the United States are sourced directly from wild populations, mostly in the western Pacific and Indian Ocean. With the US accounting for around two-thirds of all global aquarium fish imports, researchers warn that this reliance on wild capture threatens the sustainability of coral reef ecosystems and puts endangered and threatened species at greater risk of extinction.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-nemo-aquarium-fish-caught-wild.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 11:00:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678986881</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/losing-nemo-almost-all.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>The space beyond our planet is a long way from empty and a long way from boring</title>
                    <description>We all need some space sometimes—but it&#039;s harder to find than you might think. How far into our universe do we have to go to reach somewhere truly empty?</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-space-planet.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:47:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679049221</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/space-is-full-of-dust.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Microwave technique allows energy-efficient chemical reactions</title>
                    <description>Some industrial processes used to create useful chemicals require heat, but heating methods are often inefficient, partly because they heat a greater volume of space than they really need to. Researchers, including those from the University of Tokyo, devised a way to limit heating to the specific areas required in such situations. Their technique uses microwaves, not unlike those used in home microwave ovens, to excite specific elements dispersed in the materials to be heated. Their system proved to be around 4.5 times more efficient than current methods.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-microwave-technique-energy-efficient-chemical.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 14:00:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679312408</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/microwaves-for-energy.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Freely levitating rotor spins out ultraprecise sensors for classical and quantum physics</title>
                    <description>With a clever design, researchers have solved eddy-current damping in macroscopic levitating systems, paving the way for a wide range of sensing technologies.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-freely-levitating-rotor-ultraprecise-sensors.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 05:00:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679159441</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/freely-levitating-roto.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Scientists discover hidden gecko species in Atacama desert</title>
                    <description>Beneath the relentless sun of Chile&#039;s Atacama Desert, tiny geckos hide a remarkable secret. New genomic research, led by the University of Wollongong&#039;s (UOW) Kamryn Carter, has discovered that these resilient reptiles, known as Garthia geckos or Chilean marked geckos, comprise up to 11 distinct species, not the single species scientists previously thought.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-scientists-hidden-gecko-species-atacama.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 08:32:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679044721</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/scientists-discover-hi-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Strange &#039;rogue&#039; planet spotted guzzling matter like a star</title>
                    <description>A mysterious &quot;rogue&quot; planet has been observed gobbling six billion tons of gas and dust a second—an unprecedented rate that blurs the line between planets and stars, astronomers said Thursday.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-strange-rogue-planet-guzzling-star.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 10:30:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678619838</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/an-artists-impression-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Seeing double: Visual anagrams that rotate open doors for brain research</title>
                    <description>New artificial intelligence-generated images that appear to be one thing, but something else entirely when rotated, are helping scientists test the human mind.</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-visual-anagrams-rotate-doors-brain.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:00:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678703924</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/seeing-double-clever-i.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Discovery of binary stars the first step in creating &#039;movie of the universe&#039;</title>
                    <description>A discovery of binary stars could be the first step in building a more complete picture of how our galaxy formed, according to astronomers from The Australian National University (ANU). The discovery is part of an ambitious 10-year program to scan the entire southern sky every few nights.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-discovery-binary-stars-movie-universe.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 10:56:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679226161</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/discovery-of-binary-st.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>How marine heat waves reshape ocean food webs and slow deep sea carbon transport</title>
                    <description>New research shows that marine heat waves can reshape ocean food webs, which in turn can slow the transport of carbon to the deep sea and hamper the ocean&#039;s ability to buffer against climate change.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-marine-reshape-ocean-food-webs.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 05:00:05 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678704462</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/marine-heatwaves-have.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Physics-informed AI excels at large-scale discovery of new materials</title>
                    <description>One of the key steps in developing new materials is property identification, which has long relied on massive amounts of experimental data and expensive equipment, limiting research efficiency. A KAIST research team has introduced a new technique that combines physical laws, which govern deformation and interaction of materials and energy, with artificial intelligence. This approach allows for rapid exploration of new materials even under data-scarce conditions and provides a foundation for accelerating design and verification across multiple engineering fields, including materials, mechanics, energy, and electronics.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-physics-ai-excels-large-scale.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 11:04:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679313041</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/physics-informed-ai-ex.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>With new analysis, Apollo samples brought to Earth in 1972 reveal exotic sulfur hidden in moon&#039;s mantle</title>
                    <description>When astronauts returned from NASA&#039;s final Apollo moon mission in 1972, some of the samples they collected were sealed and carefully stored away in the hope that future researchers using advanced equipment might analyze them and make new discoveries.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-analysis-apollo-samples-brought-earth.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 17:08:06 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678989281</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/with-new-analysis-apol.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Microplastics found to change gut microbiome in first human-sample study</title>
                    <description>New research presented at UEG Week 2025 shows that microplastics—plastic particles smaller than 5 mm commonly found in the environment—can alter the human gut microbiome, with some changes resembling patterns linked to depression and colorectal cancer.</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-microplastics-gut-microbiome-human-sample.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:33:50 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679048425</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/microplastics-found-to.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Bacteria may influence accumulation of gold nanoparticles in spruce tree needles</title>
                    <description>A new study has, for the first time, uncovered a connection between bacteria living in Norway spruce needles and gold nanoparticles. This discovery could pave the way for environmentally friendly gold exploration methods, while examining similar processes in mosses may also help remove metals from mining-impacted waters.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-bacteria-accumulation-gold-nanoparticles-spruce.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 16:17:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678986222</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/golden-spruce-trees-go.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Americans, Canadians unite in battling &#039;eating machine&#039; carp</title>
                    <description>Finally, something to unite President Donald Trump, his Democratic opponents and the Canadians he&#039;s threatening to annex: a ferociously hungry carp.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-americans-canadians-machine-carp.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Sun, 05 Oct 2025 12:40:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678886283</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/a-team-from-canadas-fi.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>North American ice sheets drove dramatic sea-level rise at end of last ice age, study finds</title>
                    <description>Melting ice sheets in North America played a far greater role in driving global sea-level rise at the end of the last ice age than scientists had thought, according to a Tulane University-led study published in Nature Geoscience.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-north-american-ice-sheets-drove.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 05:00:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679137482</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/north-american-ice-she.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Inhalers drive carbon emissions equivalent to 530,000 cars each year, study shows</title>
                    <description>Inhalers are the frontline treatment for asthma and COPD, but they come with a steep environmental cost, according to a new UCLA Health study—the largest to date quantifying inhaler-related emissions in the United States.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-inhalers-carbon-emissions-equivalent-cars.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:00:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678704641</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/inhaler-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>California physicist and Nobel laureate John Martinis won&#039;t quit on quantum computers</title>
                    <description>A California physicist and Nobel laureate who laid the foundation for quantum computing isn&#039;t done working.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-california-physicist-nobel-laureate-john.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 05:57:50 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679294660</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/quantum-computer.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Scientists create nanofluidic chip with &#039;brain-like&#039; memory pathways</title>
                    <description>Scientists at Monash University have created a tiny fluid-based chip that behaves like neural pathways of the brain, potentially opening the door to a new generation of computers.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-scientists-nanofluidic-chip-brain-memory.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 09:55:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679308901</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/scientists-create-nano.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>What are regulatory T-cells? Nobel-winning science explained</title>
                    <description>The Nobel Prize in Medicine was awarded on Monday to three scientists for discovering how a particular kind of cell can stop the body&#039;s immune system from attacking itself.</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-regulatory-cells-nobel-science.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:30:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678968766</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/a-us-japanese-trio-won.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Stretchable waveguides maintain stable transmission even when bent or twisted</title>
                    <description>Researchers have designed and demonstrated stretchable waveguides that maintain efficient, stable signal transmission of surface plasmon polaritons even when bent, twisted or stretched. These plasmonic waveguides could make it possible to seamlessly embed advanced sensing, communication and health monitoring functions into everyday wearable materials.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-stretchable-waveguides-stable-transmission-bent.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 14:28:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678979681</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/stretchable-waveguides-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Strontium optical lattice clock exhibits record-high coherence time</title>
                    <description>Optical lattice clocks are emerging timekeeping devices based on tens of thousands of ultracold atoms trapped in an optical lattice (i.e., a grid of laser light). By oscillating between two distinct quantum states at a particular frequency, these atoms could help to measure time with much higher precision than existing clocks, which would be highly advantageous for the study of various fundamental physical processes and systems.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-strontium-optical-lattice-clock-high.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:20:05 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678968109</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/a-strontium-optical-la.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>How MXenes truly work: Novel technique shines light on next-gen nanomaterials</title>
                    <description>Researchers have for the first time measured the true properties of individual MXene flakes—an exciting new nanomaterial with potential for better batteries, flexible electronics, and clean energy devices.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-mxenes-technique-gen-nanomaterials.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:23:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678964981</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/novel-technique-shines.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Could life exist on Mars today? Here&#039;s what the latest evidence says</title>
                    <description>Recently, NASA revealed exciting details of new findings from Mars. Scientists have discovered tiny patterns of unusual minerals in the clay-rich rocks on the edge of Jezero Crater—an ancient lake once fed by Martian river systems, and the exploration site of the NASA Perseverance Rover.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-life-mars-today-latest-evidence.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:43:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678969782</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/could-life-exist-on-ma.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Wheat diversity discovery could provide an urgently-needed solution to global food security</title>
                    <description>Wheat has a very large and complex genome. Researchers have found that different varieties can use their genes in different ways. By studying RNA—the molecules that carry out instructions from DNA—researchers can see which genes are active and when. By mapping this gene activity for the first time, researchers are able to accelerate international wheat breeding programs, developing new varieties of wheat which can adapt to the rapidly escalating climate emergency.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-wheat-diversity-discovery-urgently-solution.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 05:00:08 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678708301</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/wheat.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Cosmic tug-of-war: Gravity reshapes magnetic fields in star clusters</title>
                    <description>Astronomers have captured the clearest picture yet of how massive stars are born, revealing a dramatic interplay between gravity and magnetic fields in some of our galaxy&#039;s most dynamic star forming regions. A team led by Dr. Qizhou Zhang from the Center for Astrophysics | Harvard &amp; Smithsonian used the Atacama Large Millimeter/submillimeter Array (ALMA) to conduct the largest and most detailed survey to date of magnetic fields in 17 regions where clusters of massive stars are forming.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-cosmic-war-gravity-reshapes-magnetic.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:02:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679147321</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/cosmic-tug-of-war-grav.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Mysterious signs on Teotihuacan murals may reveal an early form of Uto-Aztecan language</title>
                    <description>More than two millennia ago, Teotihuacan was a thriving metropolis in central Mexico with up to 125,000 inhabitants. The city had gigantic pyramids and was a cultural center in Mesoamerica at the time.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-mysterious-teotihuacan-murals-reveal-early.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 13:12:28 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678975138</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/researchers-on-the-ver-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>We tested if a specialized magnetic powder could remove microplastics from drinking water: The answer is yes</title>
                    <description>Microplastics are the crumbs of our plastic world, tiny pieces that come from bigger items breaking apart or from products like synthetic clothing and packaging. They&#039;re now everywhere. Scientists estimate there are about 51 trillion of these particles floating in the world&#039;s surface waters, and low levels have even been found in South African tap water.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-specialized-magnetic-powder-microplastics.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:04:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679147441</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2020/3-plastic.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>How enzymes &#039;dance&#039; while they work, and why that&#039;s important</title>
                    <description>Researchers from Tokyo Metropolitan University have developed a new structure determination method using nuclear magnetic resonance (NMR) spectroscopy which shows how different parts of complex molecular machinery like enzymes move while they help catalyze reactions. The research is published in the Journal of the American Chemical Society.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-enzymes-important.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 08:54:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678959641</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/scientists-glimpse-how.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Researchers develop the first miniaturized ultraviolet spectrometer chip</title>
                    <description>Recently, the iGaN Laboratory led by Professor Haiding Sun at the School of Microelectronics, University of Science and Technology of China (USTC), together with the team of academician Sheng Liu from Wuhan University, has successfully developed the world&#039;s first miniaturized ultraviolet (UV) spectrometer chip and realized on-chip spectral imaging.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-miniaturized-ultraviolet-spectrometer-chip.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 09:54:52 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678963281</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/ustc-igan-researchers.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Tiny engine runs hotter than the sun to probe the frontiers of thermodynamics</title>
                    <description>Scientists have created the world&#039;s hottest engine running at temperatures hotter than those reached in the sun&#039;s core. The team from King&#039;s College London and collaborators believe their platform could provide an unparalleled understanding of the laws of thermodynamics on a small scale, and provide the foundation for a new, efficient way to compute how proteins fold—the subject of last year&#039;s Nobel Prize in Chemistry.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-tiny-hotter-sun-probe-frontiers.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 09:55:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679222501</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/scientists-create-worl-2.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Gravitational lenses imaged by Webb during its first run</title>
                    <description>Periodically, the European Space Agency (ESA) releases images that provide breathtaking views of the cosmos, courtesy of its premier missions. This includes a relative newcomer to party with the ESA/Webb Picture of the Month, which showcases the high-resolution and ultra-sensitive capabilities of the James Webb Space Telescope (JWST). This month&#039;s feature: eight stunning images of gravitationally-lensed galaxies observed by Webb during its Cycle 1 General Observation (GO) surveys. The study of these lensed galaxies is providing insight into the early universe and how galaxies have evolved with time.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-gravitational-lenses-imaged-webb.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 09:49:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679049341</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/check-out-these-gravit.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Blood cancer: Scientists reprogram cancer cell death to trigger immune system</title>
                    <description>The aim of immunotherapy strategies is to leverage cells in the patient&#039;s own immune system to destroy tumor cells. Using a preclinical model, scientists from the Institut Pasteur and Inserm successfully stimulated an effective anti-tumor immune response by reprogramming the death of malignant B cells. They demonstrated an effective triple-therapy approach for treating forms of blood cancer such as certain lymphomas and leukemias which affect B cells. The study was published on August 15 in the journal Science Advances.</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-blood-cancer-scientists-reprogram-cell.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 12:54:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679319641</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/blood-cancer-a-treatme.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Digital twin for forests developed with help of new laser scan technology</title>
                    <description>Scanning forests with lasers can provide three-dimensional models of forests, creating a unique way to look at these ecosystems. Researchers at the University of Helsinki are pioneers in applying this technical solution to measuring ecosystems.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-digital-twin-forests-laser-scan.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 15:29:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678983342</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/digital-twin-for-fores.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>The Nobel Prize in medicine goes to 3 scientists for key immune system discoveries</title>
                    <description>Three scientists won the Nobel Prize in medicine Monday for discoveries about how the immune system knows to attack germs and not our own bodies.</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-nobel-prize-medicine-scientists-peripheral.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 05:42:18 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678948127</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/the-nobel-prize-in-med-2.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>&#039;People are going to die&#039;: Idahoans fear spike in insurance costs</title>
                    <description>At 59, Susan Wood, a longtime Boise, Idaho, resident, was too young to qualify for Medicare when she retired in July. So she signed up for a marketplace plan under the Affordable Care Act, often called Obamacare.</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-people-die-idahoans-spike.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 06:27:41 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679123656</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/health-insurance.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Breakthrough mirror-image nanopores open door to new biomedical applications</title>
                    <description>For the first time, researchers have successfully fabricated and characterized a fully functional mirror-image nanopore—a molecular gateway built entirely from D-amino acids, the mirror-image forms of the natural building blocks of proteins. The work, led by Prof. Dr. Kozhinjampara R. Mahendran at the Rajiv Gandhi Center for Biotechnology (India) in collaboration with Constructor University and other partners, demonstrates not only a major milestone in nanoscience but also opens promising biomedical applications, including potential cancer therapies.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-breakthrough-mirror-image-nanopores-door.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 12:20:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679317304</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/breakthrough-mirror-im-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Physicists improve precision of atomic clocks by reducing quantum noise</title>
                    <description>Every time you check the time on your phone, make an online transaction, or use a navigation app, you are depending on the precision of atomic clocks.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-physicists-precision-atomic-clocks-quantum.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 13:05:05 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679147502</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/physicists-improve-the.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Splitting water: How order and disorder direct chemical reactivity</title>
                    <description>In nature, the behavior of systems—whether large or small—is always governed by a few fundamental principles. For instance, objects fall downward because it minimizes their energy. At the same time, order and disorder are key variables that also shape physical processes. Systems—especially our homes—tend to become increasingly disordered over time. Even at the microscopic level, systems tend to favor increased disorder, a phenomenon known as an increase in so-called entropy.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-disorder-chemical-reactivity.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:29:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679066141</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/how-order-and-disorder.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>We need a solar sail probe to detect space tornadoes earlier, researchers say</title>
                    <description>Spirals of solar wind can spin off larger solar eruptions and disrupt Earth&#039;s magnetic field, yet they are too difficult to detect with our current single-location warning system, according to a new study from the University of Michigan.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-solar-probe-space-tornadoes-earlier.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 12:00:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678707582</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/we-need-a-solar-sail-p.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>1,000-year-old gut microbiome revealed for young man who lived in pre-Hispanic Mexico</title>
                    <description>Analysis of preserved feces and intestinal tissue has revealed specific types of bacteria that were present in the microbiome of a young adult man who lived in Mexico about 1,000 years ago, prior to Spanish colonization. Santiago Rosas-Plaza of Universidad Nacional Autónoma de México and colleagues present these findings in PLOS One.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-year-gut-microbiome-revealed-young.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 14:00:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678988441</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/1000-year-old-gut-micr.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Hot gaseous outflow detected in the galaxy NGC 5746</title>
                    <description>Using ESA&#039;s XMM-Newton satellite, astronomers have conducted deep observations of a massive galaxy known as NGC 5746. As a result, they detected a hot gaseous outflow in the galaxy. The new findings, presented Oct. 1 on the arXiv pre-print server, could shed more light on the nature of NGC 5746.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-hot-gaseous-outflow-galaxy-ngc.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 08:30:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679138064</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/hot-gaseous-outflow-de.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>AI tool helps match enzymes to substrates</title>
                    <description>A new artificial intelligence-powered tool can help researchers determine how well an enzyme fits with a desired target, helping them find the best enzyme and substrate combination for applications from catalysis to medicine to manufacturing.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-ai-tool-enzymes-substrates.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:39:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679156741</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2015/enzyme.png" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Schizophrenia is linked to iron and myelin deficits in the brain, neuroimaging study finds</title>
                    <description>Schizophrenia is a severe and debilitating psychiatric disorder characterized by hallucinations, disorganized speech and thought patterns, false beliefs about the world or oneself, difficulties concentrating and other symptoms impacting people&#039;s daily functioning. While schizophrenia has been the topic of numerous research studies, its biological and neural underpinnings have not yet been fully elucidated.</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-schizophrenia-linked-iron-myelin-deficits.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 07:30:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679149715</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/schizophrenia-is-linke.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Widely-prescribed opioid painkiller tramadol not significantly effective for easing chronic pain, analysis finds</title>
                    <description>The strong opioid painkiller tramadol is not significantly effective at easing the chronic pain for which it&#039;s widely prescribed, finds a pooled data analysis of the available research, published in BMJ Evidence-Based Medicine.</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-widely-opioid-painkiller-tramadol-significantly.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 18:30:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678981662</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2024/opioids-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Questionable lead reporting for drinking water virtually vanished after Flint water crisis, study reveals</title>
                    <description>Public water systems in the U.S. were far less likely to report suspiciously rounded lead levels after the Flint, Michigan water crisis drew national outrage and federal scrutiny, according to new research led by the University of Massachusetts Amherst.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-virtually-flint-crisis-reveals.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:55:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679067701</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2023/water-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Researchers elucidate aging mechanisms and identify a biomarker for aging and overall health status</title>
                    <description>Aging is a systemic process that affects the entire body. Visible external signs of aging usually correspond to evidence of equivalent aging in the functioning of the internal organs. This indicates that skin cells age in tandem with other cells throughout the body, suggesting a mechanism whereby aging in one part of the body spreads systemically.</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-elucidate-aging-mechanisms-biomarker-health.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 12:24:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679317841</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/researchers-elucidate.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Rocket test proves bacteria survive space launch and re-entry unharmed</title>
                    <description>A world-first study has proven microbes essential for human health can survive the extreme forces of space launch. The study has been published in npj Microgravity.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-rocket-bacteria-survive-space-entry.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 05:00:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678701281</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/rocket-test-proves-bac.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Africa&#039;s &#039;great green wall&#039; is stalling: In Senegal very few planted areas show progress</title>
                    <description>Africa&#039;s Great Green Wall project began as an ambitious plan to build a 15-kilometer-wide band of trees across the north of Africa. The African Union launched the project in 2007 with plans for the trees to extend for 6,000 kilometers through 11 countries in the Sahel, restoring 100 million hectares of land from Senegal to Djibouti and Ethiopia. Its main aim was to prevent the Sahara Desert from advancing. But the Great Green Wall&#039;s also been billed as a solution to climate change, poverty, and even extremism.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-africa-great-green-wall-stalling.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 12:31:05 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679059062</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/africas-great-green-wa-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Take a flight over the Martian surface with the Mars Express orbiter</title>
                    <description>For more than twenty years, the Mars Express orbiter has studied the Red Planet and remains the European Space Agency&#039;s (ESA) only operational mission. In that time, it has provided the most complete map of the Martian atmosphere and its chemical composition. It has also studied Mars&#039;s innermost moon (Phobos) in stunning detail, and traced the flow channels, delta fans, and chaos terrain that demonstrate that liquid water once flowed on the planet&#039;s surface. In addition, the images taken by the orbiter have been used to create detailed mosaics that have breathtaking 3D views of the landscape.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-flight-martian-surface-mars-orbiter.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 11:14:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678968042</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/take-a-flight-over-the.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Living near toxic Superfund sites linked to aggressive breast cancer</title>
                    <description>Breast cancer is the second leading cause of cancer death among women, according to the American Cancer Society. Now, three recent studies by researchers at Sylvester Comprehensive Cancer Center, part of the University of Miami Miller School of Medicine, have uncovered links between breast cancer, Superfund sites and social adversity.</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-toxic-superfund-sites-linked-aggressive.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Sat, 11 Oct 2025 09:50:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679322503</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/living-near-toxic-site-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Superconductivity distorts crystal lattice of topological quantum materials</title>
                    <description>Superconductors (materials that conduct electricity without resistance) have fascinated physicists for more than a century. While conventional superconductors are well understood, a new class of materials known as topological superconductors has attracted intense interest in recent years.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-superconductivity-distorts-crystal-lattice-topological.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Oct 2025 11:32:03 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679228321</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/superconductivity-dist.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>A stevia-derived sweetener could improve hair loss treatment</title>
                    <description>Androgenetic alopecia is a common form of hair loss in both men and women—also called male pattern baldness and female pattern hair loss. Topical minoxidil is an approved treatment, but it has poor water solubility and skin permeability. New research in Advanced Healthcare Materials reveals that stevioside, a natural sweetener derived from the stevia plant, can improve the drug&#039;s absorption into the skin.</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-stevia-derived-sweetener-hair-loss.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 03:10:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678983101</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2017/steviarebaud.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Chip-based phonon splitter brings hybrid quantum networks closer to reality</title>
                    <description>Researchers have created a chip-based device that can split phonons—tiny packets of mechanical vibration that can carry information in quantum systems. By filling a key gap, this device could help connect various quantum devices via phonons, paving the way for advanced computing and secure quantum communication.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-chip-based-phonon-splitter-hybrid.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Mon, 06 Oct 2025 10:00:05 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678963061</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/chip-based-phonon-spli.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Scientists discover regulatory pathway behind cyanobacteria&#039;s carbon-fixing factories</title>
                    <description>Long before plants and algae, cyanobacteria were already performing photosynthesis—filling Earth&#039;s skies with oxygen and setting the stage for life as we know it. The ultra-prevalent bacteria are critical to the global carbon cycle, responsible for fixing as much as 30% of the world&#039;s carbon dioxide and converting it into oxygen we breathe. And because they&#039;re the simplest organisms that carry out this complex process, they&#039;re both ideal for studying fundamentals of biology as well as promising contenders for bioengineering.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-scientists-regulatory-pathway-cyanobacteria-carbon.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:14:40 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679155275</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/scientists-discover-re.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Instructions help you remember something better than emotions or a good night&#039;s sleep, scientists find</title>
                    <description>A good night&#039;s sleep has long been understood to help us consolidate new memories, but we don&#039;t understand how. Associations with negative feelings like fear or stress can improve recall, but intentionally trying to remember can also be effective. But these two mechanisms are very different—one involuntary, one deliberate. Which influences memory most?</description>
                    <link>https://medicalxpress.com/news/2025-10-emotions-good-night-scientists.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 00:00:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news678958321</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2017/remember.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Chinese medicine extract tetrandrine&#039;s precise mechanism of action opens new avenues for drug discovery</title>
                    <description>A research team led by Prof. Ben Ko Chi-bun, Associate Professor of the PolyU Department of Applied Biology and Chemical Technology, has discovered the critical mechanism of action of tetrandrine, a compound derived from Chinese medicine Stephania tetrandra. Their work opens the door to innovative treatments for viral infections and neurodegenerative disorders like Alzheimer&#039;s and Parkinson&#039;s.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-chinese-medicine-tetrandrine-precise-mechanism.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 15:20:02 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679155286</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/researchers-uncover-ta-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Bamboo-based plastic can be made to biodegrade quickly, but still holds up in tough conditions</title>
                    <description>A new method to produce strong, biodegradable plastic from bamboo is reported in Nature Communications this week. The bioplastic resembles oil-based plastics in strength, shapability, and thermal stability but can biodegrade in soil within 50 days, presenting a new pathway toward sustainable plastic alternatives.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-bamboo-based-plastic-biodegrade-quickly.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:15:02 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679065301</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/bamboo-based-plastic-c.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Strain engineering enhances spin readout in quantum technologies, study shows</title>
                    <description>Quantum defects are tiny imperfections in solid crystal lattices that can trap individual electrons and their &quot;spin&quot; (i.e., the internal angular momentum of particles). These defects are central to the functioning of various quantum technologies, including quantum sensors, computers and communication systems.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-strain-readout-quantum-technologies.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Oct 2025 06:30:01 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679233299</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/strain-is-an-effective-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                            <item>
                    <title>Leafcutter ants have blind spots, just like truck drivers</title>
                    <description>We have all been in that situation: The moving boxes are large and heavy, but we are determined to carry them all in one trip, even if that means we can&#039;t see where we&#039;re going. In the tropics, some leafcutter ants face a similar challenge: carrying a load that is several times their body weight. To make matters even more difficult, carrying oversized weights may create &quot;blind spots&quot; when leafcutter ants transport material on a trail.</description>
                    <link>https://phys.org/news/2025-10-leafcutter-ants-truck-drivers.html</link>
                    <category>
                                                    
                                            </category>
                    <pubDate>Tue, 07 Oct 2025 14:27:04 EDT</pubDate>
                    <guid isPermaLink="false">news679066022</guid>
                                            <media:thumbnail url="https://scx1.b-cdn.net/csz/news/tmb/2025/leafcutter-ants-have-b-1.jpg" width="90" height="90" />
                                    </item>
                        
</channel>
</rss>